# **Nandor Tibor Szots**

## Personal Profile

Self-motivated engineering leader who enjoys mentoring his teams to achieve their full potential. Extensive experience in building, coaching, and motivating teams of engineers to consistently deliver results on aggressive timelines. I also have a proven track record of designing practical solutions to complex problems, while ensuring maintainability and reusability.

# Work Experience

Amazon July 2016 - Present

Position: Manager, Software Development III

Currently leading an organization comprised of 3 teams with 24 people. Responsible for key parts of Amazons PrimeNow and Fresh businesses. I direct the product roadmap, software development, and operational excellence for these teams. We own systems that handle 250k+TPS in sub-millisecond latency with 99% uptime and 24/7 engineering support.

I lead teams in integrating key parts of the Whole Foods and Amazon Fresh shopping experience on Amazon.com. This includes:

- Customer Notifications Desktop, Mobile, SMS, and Email event-based notifications
- Automated Refunds Event-Based Refunds which has eliminated 100+ hours of manual CS work per week
- Modeling all Whole Foods and Fresh Stores Data Data Models, Storage, and Lookup capabilities
  of all worldwide stores with low latency and high availability requirements

I led a team in creating Amazon Fresh Order Modifications. This contributed to significant increases in units per order (UPO) and average order size (AOS). This team was based across San Diego, Irvine, and Seattle.

In addition to the normal scope of my teams, I worked with business leaders in the EU to build a new mobile bottle returns app for our delivery drivers. I proposed a fast to market solution built on AWS and native iOS to launch on time while also meeting all business requirements.

I also designed and implemented a brand new hiring pipeline for the San Diego Amazon site. This included new processes, procedures, candidate tracking, and metrics. Using this pipeline, we successfully hired over 150 engineers in 12 months and increased the population of the site by 9-fold over 3 years. I then created a recommended best practices guide. This guide is now implemented by 4 other sites globally.

#### Sony Online Entertainment

January 2013 - July 2016

Position: Technical Director

Projects: EverQuest II, EverQuest Next and EverQuest Landmark

Worked with other technical personnel on developing new company-wide technologies. Helped design and architect key systems for new and existing games.

Built and lead the EverQuest II team as both a technical leader and people manager. Responsible for both key technical decisions as well as personnel decisions on EverQuest II. Played an integral role in the hiring processes for the EverQuest Franchise.

Lead teams of C++ and Web Developers in building the in-game marketplace and showcase for display and real-time sale of both player and SOE created items - Landmark Showcase. This feature was designed and brought to market in a record 6 months and accounts for over 50% of the profits of the game.

Designed, architected and lead the team in implementing:

• Backend C++ servers which control the searching of and sale of these items.

- Recommendation system to suggest purchases to users.
- UI for creating player-made items, along with UI Artists and Producers to make sure all needs were met.
- Mobile and Desktop web-based UI through which players can search for and find items to purchase.
- Daily digest email of products that is personalized based on a user's interests.
- Mobile and Desktop shopping UX support.

daily tasking of the EverQuest II code team.

#### Sony Online Entertainment

January 2012 - January 2013

Position: Lead Programmer Project: EverQuest II

Lead a team of programmers in developing new features and refreshing, enhancing and giving new purpose to previously used features in the popular EverQuest II MMORPG. Responsible for architecting new systems, Full Team scheduling, project time estimates, and

### Sony Online Entertainment

January 2006 - January 2012

Position: Senior Programmer Project: EverQuest II

Implemented the EverQuest II and EverQuest II: Extended marketplace functionality including: all back-end commerce and server-side communications. Transitioned the original implementation of the marketplace into a highly successful Free-to-Play model, while maintaining a non-Free-to-Play service as well.

Responsible for all marketplace improvements, changes, and new technology development.

Lead the development of a mobile companion app for the core game which allowed players to interact with the game world and participate in activities such as crafting and chat from their mobile devices.

Designed and implemented a tool for third-party sites to be able to obtain information about in-game characters, items, and spells. This system used EDB and X-Path to index XML blob data for fast searching of relevant game data.

Implemented a bayesian filter for all game messages to combat the growing spam problems. The filter has a 99% accuracy rate and blocks on the order of 500,000 messages per day.

General Atomics - Lynx Systems

January 2003 - January 2006

Position: Lead Software Engineer

AudioTalk Inc. / HearMe Inc.

June 1998 - July 2001

Position: Junior Engineer / Operations Engineer

University of California, Santa Cruz

December 1998 - December 2002

Position: Student Grader/Lab Assistant/Volunteer Tutor

University of California, Santa Cruz

December 1998 - June 2000

Position: Residential Computer Coordinator

Affiliations

University of California, San Diego San Diego State University

Corporate Affiliates Board Aztec Mentor Program

Education

University of California, Santa Cruz

1998 - 2002

B.S. in Computer Science.